JOAKIM RYLANDER

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

rylander.j92@gmail.com | +46 (0)765-578421 | Stockholm, Sweden | www.linkedin.com/in/joerylander/

SUMMARY

Frontend Developer 3+ years of experience working in web development, specializing in building responsive, user-friendly and dynamic web applications. Additional experience with version control, CI/CD pipelines, test-driven development, as well as close collaboration with UI/UX and backend teams. Comfortable working in Agile environments with a strong focus on team-driven development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer, Odevo AB

April 2023 - Present

- Developed and maintained an internal ERP SaaS platform for property and financial management
- Built and improved a customer-facing portal for managing errands, finances, and housing services
- Created a public-facing website builder for housing associations (BRFs), editable through the private platform
- · Worked closely with stakeholders to deliver user-focused features with clean, responsive design

Full stack Developer Consultant, TT News Agency AB

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

- Developed a full-stack web application to present and manage Swedish election data for end users
- Built a user-facing web interface using modern frontend frameworks
- Designed and implemented a RESTful API with full CRUD functionality to support data interactions
- Developed, and maintained a relational SQL database for persistent & scalable data management

Full stack Developer, School of Applied Technology AB

Sep 2021 - Jan 2023

- · Completed intensive 3-month full stack JavaScript bootcamp focused on modern web development
- Hired post-bootcamp to work as a consultant on client projects

SKILLS

Javascript, html, css, react, next.js, node.js, angular, php, sql, responsive design, git, restful api, docker, figma, debugging, ci/cd, attention to detail, problem-solving, communication, time management, critical thinking, organizational skills, agile, kanban, independent, teamwork, pair programming

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computers and Systems Sciences

Class of 2024

Stockholm University

· Relevant coursework: Web Development, HCI, Data Structures, Databases & IS

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: Swedish, English

· Certifications: Professional Kanban License